After Daddy died, Kaoru and Tomoki were separated.
（薫）＜パパが死んで　薫と友樹は 離れ離れになりました＞
But Daddy's friend Marumo
＜でも　パパのお友達のマルモが→
said we could live with him.
一緒に暮らそうって 言ってくれました＞
Along with a dog called Mook.
＜ムックという犬も一緒です＞
That's so tacky~.
（ムック）だっせ～。
-Why? It's cute. -You're kidding me.
（薫）何で？　カワイイじゃん。 （護）嘘でしょ？
We made an Okite* Notebook (*rules/code)
＜３人で 仲良く暮らしていくために→
so that the three of us can live together happily.
おきてノートを作りました＞
Kaoru and Tomoki are first graders now.
＜薫と友樹は １年生になりました＞
So this time the dog said "That's so tacky."
（桜子）今度は　「ださい」と 言ったわけですね　犬が。
Yes. The dog said "That's so tacky."
ええ 「ださい」と言ったんです　犬が。
And you're saying that the children even talked with him.
さらに　子供たちまで 一緒に　しゃべったと。
Yes. What does this mean?
はい どういうことなんでしょうか。
Generally speaking,
総合的に 判断させていただきますと→
I think you and the twins have the same symptoms.
高木さんも　双子のお子さんたちも同じ症状だと考えられます。
What you have in common is
共通しているのは→
the fact that all of you just recently lost a loved one.
大切な人を亡くしたばかり ということです。
-So what should we do? -There are
それで　どうすれば？ 幻聴には→
several ways to treat auditory hallucination, but
様々な治療法がありますが→
in your case, the worst thing you can do
高木さんたちの場合 一番　良くないのは→
is to overreact.
過剰に反応し過ぎることです。 えっ？
Be careful not to overreact every time you have
幻聴だからと　いちいち騒いだり→
an auditory hallucination, but don't ignore it either.
逆に　無視したりしないように 注意してください。
Just listen to the voice with a calm mind,
心を穏やかにして ありのままに耳を傾け→
and try to appreciate the experience.
その体験を尊重するんです。
-I see. -If you relax and accept it,
なるほど。 リラックスして向き合えば→
it may go away naturally.
自然に幻聴が消えるケースも あります。
Got it. Relax, right? Relax.
分かりました リラックスですね　リラックス。
Alright.
（杉下）よし→
Before we being the class today, let's decide on the duties.
今日は授業を始める前に クラスの係を決めよう。→
Have you all thought of which duty you might want?
みんな やりたい係　考えてきたか？
Yes~.
（一同）は～い。
I want health duty.
（健太）僕　保健係がいい。
Me too. We get to take our classmates to the health room, right?
（友樹）僕も。　お友達を 保健室に連れていくんでしょ？
Yes. But you'd better think twice if you think
（杉下）ああ。　だからって 授業をサボれると思ったら→
you can skip out on classes.
大間違いだぞ。 えっ？
Listen. Duties aren't games.
（杉下）いいか？ 係はな　遊びじゃないんだ。→
I want you all to learn the importance
先生は　この係活動を通じて→
of doing your best through these duties.
みんなが　頑張ることの大切さを 学んでほしいと思ってる。→
And I want you to shine brilliantly.
そして きらきらと輝いてほしいんだな。
-Brilliantly? -Yes.
（薫）きらきら？ （杉下）そう→
That's my dream as a first time first grade teacher.
それが　初めて１年生を担任した 先生の夢だ。
What a small dream.
（隼人）ちっちゃい夢。 （杉下）えっ？
My dream's to be an astronaut.
僕の夢は宇宙飛行士。
Mine is Precure*. (*anime series)
（まなみ）わたしはプリキュア。
Okay, quiet now.
（杉下）はい　静かに。→
Anyway, our dream is not what matters now.
まっ　まあな　今　夢の話は もう　どうでもいい。→
For the time being, let's decide on the duties.
取りあえず　係を決めよう。→
Raise your hand for the duty you want.
やりたい係に みんな　手　挙げてくれ。→
If I get too many volunteers, we'll do rock paper scissors.
希望者が多い場合は じゃんけんするぞ。
Okay, who wants the blackboard duty?
（杉下）はい じゃ　黒板係　やりたい人。
That's too bad.
（真島）困りましたね。
Yeah. They're talking about suing us.
（鮫島）うん 相手は訴えると言ってる。
Good morning. What's wrong?
お疲れさまです。 あれ？　どうしたんすか？
There's trouble in the PR department.
（凛花）広報部で トラブっちゃったんですよ。
Takagi-kun,
えっ？ （鮫島）高木君→
I know it's sudden, but can you go to Tochigi tomorrow?
急だけど　あした 栃木へ出張に行ってくんないかな。
-Tochigi? -Our flyer
栃木ですか？ （民子）うちのチラシが→
looks exactly like that of a stationery maker in Tochigi.
栃木の文房具メーカーと そっくりなの。
"Gentle to people, family budget , and earth"
「人に、　家計に、　地球にやさしい。」
The slogan's exactly the same.
コピーが同じじゃないすか。
-Seems ours came out later. -You mean we copied them?
うちの方が後出しらしいです。 パクったってこと？
Well, when we checked with the production company,
（真島）いや 発注した制作会社に確認したら→
they said they knew nothing about it. They never saw this flyer either.
まったく知らなかったそうです。 このチラシも見たこともないって。
-Seriously? -Well,
マジで？ （鮫島）まあ→
I suppose there could be such a coincidence.
こういう偶然が重なることも あるといえばあるけどね。
But even if we didn't know about it,
（民子）でも 知らなかったとはいえ→
the other company's been using this slogan since
先方は 去年から　このキャッチコピーを→
last year, and since ours is for a new product
使ってるらしいし うちは新商品だし→
I guess there's not much we can say if they accuse us of stealing their slogan.
うちが盗んだと言われても しかたがないかもね。
-It's going to be nasty. -But why I am going?
厄介だよな。 で？　何で俺が出張に？
Customer Service representatives are experts in dealing with claims.
お客様相談室は クレーム対応のプロ。
I've been asked to send one representative.
ここから　１人　出してくれって 頼まれてね。
You say expert, but
いえいえ　プロっていっても→
I haven't been here that long yet.
僕は　こっち来て まだ　日が浅いですし→
-It's more fitting that Mashima Senpai go. -Why should I go...
ここは真島先輩に。 何で俺が行くんですか…。
It sounds like Makimura-san's going from
チラシを作った責任者として→
the PR Department as the person in charge of the flyer.
広報部から 牧村さんが行くらしいですよ。
What? Makimura-san's going?
えっ？　牧村さんが？
-So will you go? -Yes. With pleasure.
行ってくれるか。 はい　喜んで。
Who wants the book duty?
（杉下）それじゃ　本係　やりたい人。
Who wants the tidying up duty?
（杉下）じゃ　整頓係　やりたい人。
Who wants the distributing duty?
配り係　やりたい人。
Kubodera-san it is. The last one is flower duty.
（杉下）久保寺さんで決まりと。 最後は花係だな。
Onee-chan's so lucky to have the book duty.
いいな　お姉ちゃんは本係で。
I need one person for the last duty. Who wants the flower duty.
（杉下）最後は１名です。 花係　やりたい人。
Me, me.
はい　はい。
Huh?
あれ？
It sounds like too much work.
めんどくさそう。
That's a girl's job.
女子のやる仕事だろ。
Don't say such a thing.
そんなこと言うもんじゃないぞ。
So Sasakura Tomoki-san will have the flower duty.
じゃ　花係は 笹倉　友樹さんで　決まりだな。
Thanks for raising your hand.
えっ。 （杉下）よく手を挙げてくれたな。
I'm happy that you did. Work hard to make a pretty flower will bloom.
先生うれしいぞ。 頑張って奇麗な花を咲かせてくれ。
Um...Yes.
あっ　はい。
I want some too.
僕も掛ける。
Yeah, go , go. Put on lots.
おお　いこう　いこう どんどんいこう　うん。
Put on lots.
どんどん掛けて。　はいはい…。
Thank you very much.
はい　はい　はい。　はい どうも　ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much. Crunchy.
ありがとうございます。　さくさく。
-Marumo, you look happy. -Do I?
マルモ　楽しそう。 そうか？
Oh, I have to go on a business trip tomorrow, okay?
あっ 俺　あした出張だから　よろしくね。
-What's a business trip? -That means I'm not going to my usual office,
出張って？ あっ　いつも行く会社じゃなくて→
but to a different place.
ほかの所に行くんだ。
I have a very important business tomorrow.
あしたは とっても大事な仕事なんだ。
I might be a little late getting home, but
少し　帰りが 遅くなるかもしれないけど→
you two be good and stay home.
２人とも おとなしく留守番していろよ。
Okay.
うん　分かった。 うん→
I'll let Oji-san downstairs know too.
下の　おじさんたちにも よく言っとくから。
Have him feed you dinner for the time being.
取りあえず 夕飯は下で食べさしてもらえ。
And, you guys. About this guy, Mook...
おっ　お前ら こいつ　ムックのことだけどさ→
Even if he talks, don't get rattled, remain calm, and act normal.
ムックが　しゃべっても 慌てず　騒がず　普通にしてろ。
-Just relax. -We're normal.
リラックスするんだ。 普通だよ。
Okay. Maybe it's normal for you guys.
うん お前らは　そうかもしれないな。
But this is important, so I want you to listen.
大事なことだから言っとくけど→
Let's just chat with Mook only when the three of us are alone.
ムックと　おしゃべりするのは ３人のときだけにしよう。
-Why? -Because people will think
どうして？ 外でさ→
we're strange if they see us talking with Mook.
俺たちと　ムックが　しゃべってると 変な人だと思われちゃうだろ？
Anyway,
（薫・友樹）ふ～ん。 うん　とにかく→
the only time you can chat with Mook is when you're at home. Okay?
ムックと　おしゃべりするのは 家の中だけ。　なっ。
Okay. I don't really get it, but got it.
ん～ よく分かんないけど分かった。
-Yeah, got it. -Got it.
うん　分かった。 分かった。
Okay, that's good.
そっ　それでよし。
Maybe I'll ask her out for dinner.
ご飯でも誘っちゃおうかな。
[Thank you so much for coming today, Takagi-san.]
（かな）《高木さん　今日は 本当に　ありがとうございました》
[If you'd like, shall we have dinner before we go?]
《あの　よかったら お食事していきませんか？》
Just kidding.
何つって。
Marumo, I put your underwear in the washer.
マルモ パンツ　洗濯機に入れといた。
Mook pooped.
ムックが　うんちしてたよ。
Come on, don't talk about things like underwear and poop.
やだ　うんちとかパンツとか 言うんじゃないよ　まったく。
-There goes my thoughts of ro-man (romance) -Marron?
ロマンも何もねえな。 マロン？
-Ro-man. -Look.
ロマン。 ねえ　これ。
We decided duties today at school.
今日　学校で　係　決めたんだ。 へえ。
I'm going to be in charge of books.
わたし　本係になったの。
You like books, don't you? What about you, Tomoki?
薫　本　好きだもんな。　友樹は？
-Flower duty. -What? What's flower duty?
花係。 えっ？　花係って？
Um..
う～んとね→
I water the flower and give it water
お花にお水をあげたり お水をあげたり→
and things like that.
あげたりするの。
All you do is water. But
水ばっかじゃねえか。 でも。
if you water too much, the flower's gonna die, you know.
お前な　水は　やり過ぎても お花が死んじゃうんだぞ。
Really?
えっ　そうなの？
This looks good.
これ　うまそう。
What should I do? I don't want flower duty after all.
どうしよう。　やっぱり 花係なんて　やりたくないよ。
I don't want the flower to die!
お花　死んじゃうの　やだよ！
It's not even blooming yet.
まだ咲いてもないでしょ。
I blew it!
あ～　失敗した！
Tomoki, flower duty's the best.
友樹　お花係は最高なんだぞ。
Ultraman and
ほら　ウルトラマンだって→
Gachapin, and Gundam
ガチャピンだって ガンダムだって→
all had flower duty, you know.
みんな　お花係だったんだよ。
Really? Awesome!
ホント？　すげえ！
Then what do I do? What should I do to make the flower bloom?
じゃ　どうすればいいの？ どうしたら　お花　咲くの？
Huh, Marumo, tell me. Huh, Marumo.
ねえ　マルモ　教えてよ。 ねえ　マルモ。
Well, um...you have to do...that...you know.
いや　あっ　じゃ あれだ　あれだ　あの→
It'll grow if you cast a magical spell...
呪文　唱えればさ　育つよ→
-Probably. -A magical spell?
たぶん　なっ。 呪文？
-What kind of magic spell? -Huh? Um...well...
どんな呪文？ えっ？　えっとね　そう…。
Woo~ Mambo!
ウ～　マンボ！　ねっ。
Cha-ra-ra-ra Woo~ Mambo?
チャラララ　ウ～　マンボ？
Right, right. That's the magical spell.
そう　そう　そう　そう　そう　そう それが魔法の呪文だ。
Got it.
分かった。
Woo~ Mambo.
ウ～　マンボ。 うん。
Mambo.
マンボ。
Did it sprout yet?
出たかな　芽。
It's not going to sprout right away.
そんな　すぐ出ないよ。
Yes. Alright.
（真島）はい　分かりました。
Yes. I'll let him know.
あっ　はい 報告しときます　はい。→
Chief, that was Takagi-san.
室長　高木さんからです。
About the company in Tochigi...
栃木の会社ですが→
The president was out and they were turned away at the door.
社長さんが留守で　事務の人に 門前払いされたそうです。
But he said he'll standby and wait with Makimura-san
でも社長さんに会えるまで 牧村さんと→
-until they can see him. -Alright.
待機するって言ってました。 （鮫島）そうか　分かった。
I wonder if the president will see them.
社長さん会ってくれますかね。
-Maybe they'll have to wait until tomorrow. -That means
あしたになっちゃったりして。 （凛花）そしたら高木さん→
-Takagi-san's spending the night with Makimura-san? -What?
牧村さんと　お泊まり？ （真島）えっ？
Something might happen.
何かが起こるかも。
Naw, naw.
（民子・真島）ないない。
Well, even if something happened, I sure envy carefree single people.
まあ　たとえ何があったとしても 独身は楽でいいわよね。
Even if they have to suddenly spend the night away, they don't have anyone to worry about.
急な泊まりでも 気兼ねする人もいないし。
Well, yes, that's true..
いや　そりゃ　そうです…。
Oh~!
《あ～！》
-The twins. -The twins?
あっ　双子。 （凛花・民子）双子？
No, um, tw--twist cap. See this twist cap here...
いや　あの　ふた　ふた　ふたがね ふたが　ほら。　ほら　ふたが。
Oh, there's Onee-chan's picture.
あっ　お姉ちゃんの絵だ。
-Oh, I see Tomoki's picture there. -Yeah.
あっ　友樹の絵　見た　これ。 ホントだ。
Tomoki-kun's picture's weird. There's no mommy in the family.
（隼人）友樹君の絵　おかしい。 家族なのにママがいない。
Kaoru-chan's too.
えっ？ （まなみ）薫ちゃんのもだ。
It's not weird.
おかしくなんかないもん。
But there's only your daddy.
（隼人）だって パパしかいないじゃん。
That's not our daddy.
それ　パパじゃないけど。
Then who is this person?
（まなみ）じゃ　この人　誰？
Marumo.
マルモ。
Is Marumo your daddy? Or your mommy?
マルモって　パパ？　ママ？
Marumo is Marumo. He's not our daddy or mommy.
マルモはマルモだよ。 パパでもママでもないよ。
What~ It IS weird.
（まなみ）え～ やっぱり　おかしいよ。
Marumo's amazing. He knows magical spells.
マルモは　すごいんだぞ。 魔法の呪文を知ってるんだぞ。
-Magical spells? -You lie.
（はるか）呪文？ （隼人）嘘つけ。
It's true. It makes the flower grow.
ホントだもん。 お花が育つんだもん。
Then say it, this magical spell.
じゃ　やってみろよ　魔法の呪文。
Alright.
いいよ。
-What's that magical spell. -Dorky~.
何　その呪文。 （隼人）だっせ～。
Wait, wait. What's going on?
（杉下）待て待て。 こら　何を騒いでるんだ？
Sensei, Hayato-kun said Tomoki-kun's picture's weird.
（はるか）先生　隼人君が 友樹君の絵　おかしいって。
You shouldn't be saying a thing like that.
（杉下）えっ そんなこと言っちゃ駄目だろう。
But...
だって。
It's tough for Sasakura-san because they don't have their parents.
笹倉さんたちはな ご両親がいなくて大変なんだ。
Don't you feel sorry for them?
かわいそうだろうが。→
You'd have a hard time too if you didn't have your mom and dad, right?
みんなだって　パパやママが いなくなったら　つらいだろ？→
So I'm asking you all to be friends with them.
だから　みんな　笹倉さんたちと 友達になってくれ。→
Try to get along. Okay?
仲良くするんだ。　いいな？
Okay, let's begin the class. Return to your seats.
（杉下）よし　じゃ　授業　始めるぞ。 席に戻ってくれ。
Takagi-san, I'm really sorry about today
（かな）高木さん 今日は　ホントに　すいません。
That's okay, it's my job.
いえ　いえ　いえ　仕事なんで。
I hope the president will understand.
社長さん 分かってくれるといいんだけど。
Yes.
はい。
I was told by my boss to negotiate for a settlement out of court
上司からは もし難航しそうだったら→
if we ran into difficulty.
示談交渉しろと言われてきました。
You mean settle it with money?
金で解決するってことですか？
Yes.  I was told the money is ready.
はい　示談金の用意があると。
All this happened because I was lacking as the person in charge.
わたしが 担当者として勉強不足だったから。
Anyway, this is my fault.
とにかく 今回のことは　わたしの責任です。
I screwed up once too.
俺もね 失敗しちゃったことあるんです。
When I was on the product development team,
えっ？ 商品開発にいたとき→
I got this idea to create a revolutionary product.
画期的な商品を作ろうと思って→
So I got the budget to do it and created it,
予算をもらって 作ったのはいいんですけど→
but it had some issues, and caused a huge loss.
これが　ちょっとトラブって 大赤字。
Consequently, I was transferred to Customer Service.
で　飛ばされて　お客様相談室。
Boy, was I mad at first.
最初はムカついたな。
I thought, why do I have to come to a place like this.
何で　俺が　こんなところにって 思って。
But recently, I began to think that
でも 最近　ちょっと思うんですよね。
it's an important job to apologize sincerely too.
誠意を持って謝ることも 大切な仕事なんだって。
Takagi-san.
高木さん。
-Let's just apologize first and see what happens. -Yes.
まずは謝っちゃいましょうよ。 はい。
I wonder if Takagi-san can get it done.
（真島）うまくいきますかね 高木さん。
He might make them even madder.
余計に怒られちゃったりして。
-That's very likely. -Or rather, was it really necessary
あるある。 （民子）ていうか　そもそも→
for us to send a representative in the first place?
うちから人員を出す必要が あったんですか？→
The PR department should take care of it.
広報部で けりをつければいいのに。
It's a good experience for Takagi-kun too.
高木君にも　いい経験だろう。
Did you make him go on purpose?
わざと行かせたんですか？
Is everything going to be alright? He's a little flaky.
（民子）大丈夫ですか？ 頼りないけど。
I like the products he came up with.
（鮫島）彼の開発した文房具 わたし　結構　好きなんだよね。
Oh that one. That eraser that won't get smaller
あっ　あれだ　あの 使っても使っても→
-no matter how much you use it. -Was there such a thing?
減らない消しゴム。 （凛花）そんなのがあったんですか？
The phantom eraser we had to stop selling because the other
消しゴムが売れなくなるからって 他社からクレームが殺到して→
companies all complained that they wouldn't be able to sell their erasers.
発売中止になっちゃった 幻の消しゴム。
He thinks of weird things, that guy.
変なこと考える男だよね。 ハハハハハ。
Haruka-chan. Do you want to come to my house today?
（まなみ）はるかちゃん 今日　うち来ない？
My mommy's going to bake a cake.
うちのママが ケーキを焼いてくれるの。
Manami-chan.
（はるか）まなみちゃん。
Oh, sorry Tomoki-kun, for talking about mommy.
（まなみ）あっ ごめんね　友樹君　ママの話。
No, that's okay. You don't have to mind me.
えっ　ううん　いいのに。
See you tomorrow. Bye bye.
じゃ　また　あした。　バイバイ。
Bye bye.
バイバイ。
Woo~ Mambo.
ウ～　マンボ。
Tomoki.
友樹。
Onee-chan.
あっ　お姉ちゃん。
-Let's go home. -Is it
帰ろう。 うん　あのさ→
weird that we don't have a mommy?
ママがいないのって おかしいのかな。
-Here. I borrowed this. -Cinderella?
はい　これ借りてきた。 『シンデレラ』？
Cinderella didn't have a real mommy either.
シンデレラだって ホントのママがいないんだよ。
But she lived happily ever after.
でも とっても幸せになったんだよ。
-Really? -Yes, so we'll be fine. Let's go.
そうなの？ うん　だから大丈夫。　帰ろう。
Okay.
分かった。
CHI-YO-KO-RE-I-TO (chocolate)
チヨコレイト。
Rock paper scissors!
（薫・友樹）じゃんけんぽん。
PA-I-NA-TSU-PU-RU (pineapple)
パイナツプル。
It's Hayato-kun.
隼人君だ。
Hayato-kun, aren't you going home?
隼人君　帰らないの？
Your family's going to worry.
おうちの人　心配するよ。
-None of your business. -Hayato-kun.
関係ないだろ。 隼人君。
You guys got it good. Sensei doesn't get mad at you.
お前らはいいよな 先生に怒られないから。
-Huh? -He thinks you're pitiable because
えっ？ 親がいないからって→
you don't have parents. It's not fair.
かわいそうだからって　ずるいよ。
-We're not pitiable. -That's favoritism.
かわいそうじゃないもん。 えこひいきだよ。
It's not favoritism.
えこひいきじゃないもん。
But he's giving you special treatment because he thinks you're pitiable.
だって　かわいそうだからって 特別扱いしてんじゃん。
We're not pitiable.
かわいそうじゃないもん。
You wanna fight?
やったな。
Help! Onee-chan's fighting with Hayato-kun.
大変　お姉ちゃんがケンカしてる 隼人君と。
-With a boy? -Is she hurt?
（陽介）男の子か。 （彩）ケガは？
-There's blood. -I'll be right there.
血が出てる。 （彩）すぐに行く。
Aya, wait.
（陽介）あっ　彩　ちょっと待て。 （彩）えっ？
-Take this with you. -Thanks. Where are they?
（陽介）これこれ　これ持っていけ。 （彩）あっ　ありがとう。　どこ？
So the boy's the one who got hurt.
（彩）ケガしたの 男の子の方だったんだ。
Kaoru-chan, did you apologize to Hayato-kun?
薫ちゃん　隼人君に謝ったの？
But I didn't do anything wrong.
だって　薫　悪くないもん。
But you made him get hurt.
（彩）でもケガさせたんだから。
You guys make up, okay?
２人とも仲直りするのよ。 分かった？
Hayato-kun, where's your house? We'll take you home.
（彩）隼人君　おうち　どこ？ 送ってくね。→
-Your mom must be worrying about you. -Leave me alone!
お母さんたち心配してるでしょ。 （隼人）うるさい！
Wait, Hayato-kun.
（彩）えっ　ちょっ　隼人君。
Isn't Hayato-kun home?
隼人君　いないの？
Doesn't look like anyone else is home either.
うん　おうちの人も誰も出ないね。
Excuse me.
（彩）あっ　すいません。
This is Taniguchi-san's residence, isn't it?
あの こちら谷口さんのお宅ですよね。
Yes. But they won't be home until
（おばさん）ええ。 だけど　夜　遅くならないと→
later at night.
帰ってこないわよ。 （彩）えっ？
-They both work. -What about Hayato-kun?
（おばさん）共働きだから。 隼人君は？
I think he's always watching TV by himself.
いつも１人で テレビ見てるみたいだけど。→
Maybe he went to the Children's Center.
児童館でも行ったのかしらね。
So Hayato-kun's by himself all the time.
（彩）隼人君 いつも独りぼっちなのか。
Maybe he was lonely even though he has mommy and daddy.
パパとママがいても さみしかったのかな。
Maybe.
（彩）そうかもね。
You should apologize to Hayato-kun at school tomorrow, okay?
（彩）あした 学校で隼人君に謝るんだよ→
For hurting him.
ケガさせたこと。
When you do something bad, you apologize.
悪いことをしたら謝る。
Takagi-san does that kind of work every day, you know.
高木さんは　毎日 そういうお仕事してるんだよ。
I think it's important to apologize.
謝るのって大事だと思うな。
Okay.
分かった。 （彩）んっ。
Marumo is family, isn't he?
ねえ　マルモって家族だよね。
Everyone said our family's weird today.
今日　みんなに おかしいって言われたんだよ。
They asked who's Marumo.
マルモって誰だよって。
Marumo's family, isn't he?
マルモは家族だよね。
Even though we don't have daddy or mommy, Marumo's family, right?
パパやママがいなくても
That's right.
そうだね。
You're living together, so you're family.
一緒に住んでるんだもん 家族だよ。
Okay, let's go.
うん。　よし　行こっか。
Sasakura-san.
（杉下）笹倉さ～ん。
Sasakura-san. No one's home?
笹倉さ～ん。　いないのかな。
Excuse me?
（陽介）何か？ （杉下）えっ？　あっ。
Is that right. That happened at school, huh?
そうですか。 学校で　そんなことがね。
Yes.
（杉下）ええ。→
I've already cautioned the children in my class.
クラスの児童たちには 注意しておきました。→
They're too young to be without parents.
あんなに小さいのに 両親がいないなんて→
I feel so sorry for them.
本当に気の毒で。
I'll do everything I can to support them.
あっ　今後も　わたしが 全力でサポートしていきますから。
Sensei.
（陽介）あっ　先生。→
I'm aware that I'm just an outsider and not their legal guardian or anything.
いや　俺は保護者でも何でもねえし関係ねえのは分かってるんだ。→
I know that, but
いや　分かってるんだけどね→
may I say something?
ちょっと 言わせてもらっていいかな。
-Yes. -Don't you think your attitude towards them
はい。 （陽介）先生の　そういう態度がさ→
is hurting them even more?
余計に　あの子たち 傷つけてんじゃねえかな。
But I'm just really concerned about those kids.
はっ？　いや　わたしは あの子たちのことを思ってですね。
I know. I know that, and
（陽介）分かってる。 それは分かってるし→
I'm grateful that you were concerned enough to come
先生が　気になって 様子を見に来てくれたってのも→
to see how they were doing.
うれしいんだ。
But,
けどね→
your feeling sorry for them is, in itself, mistaken.
かわいそうって思うこと自体が 間違ってんだよ。
Well, so
えっ？ （陽介）いや　だから→
can you treat those kids more normally,
もっと普通にね 接してやってくんねえかな→
like other kids?
あの子たちと。
Without any special treatment, just normally.
あっ。 （陽介）特別じゃなくてさ　普通に。
Isn't that the president?
あれ　社長さんじゃないですか？
-Let's go. -Yes.
行きましょう。 （かな）はい。
Excuse me, we're from Akebono Office Supplies.
（かな）社長 あけぼの文具の者です。
Akebono Office Supplies? I don't have anything to say to you. Please leave.
（社長）あけぼの文具？ 話すことなんてない。　帰ってくれ。
We apologize for the trouble we've caused you.
このたびは　ご迷惑をお掛けして 申し訳ございませんでした。
It was really a coincidence. It's not that we stole it.
本当に偶然だったんです。 盗用したわけではなくて。
Whatever the reason, everyone thinks that we're the ones who copied you.
そう言われてもね　世間じゃ うちが　まねしたと思うんだよ。
That's the disadvantage of being a small business out here in the provinces.
地方の弱小企業の 弱みってやつでね。
-However... -We're being slandered on the internet,
ですが。 （社長）ネットで中傷されたり→
and getting complaints and inquiries as to whether they're the same products.
同じ商品なのかと 問い合わせやクレームが来たり。
Our reputation's been tattered.
うちの信用は　ぼろぼろだよ。
Sir, in regards to that,
社長　その件については→
our attorney can work out something that's agreeable...
うちの弁護士から 納得のいくような…。
How can I be agreeable to anything.
納得なんていくわけないだろう。
Once the damage is done, you can't undo it.
一度　持たれたイメージは 変わらないんだ。
You're an eyesore. Leave.
目障りなんだよ　帰ってくれ。
We're really sorry.
ホントに 申し訳ございませんでした。
The responsibility is completely ours.
責任は全て私どもにあります。
We recalled all the flyers as well.
チラシも全て回収しました。
So what.
（社長）だから何だ。
That's not going to change anything for us.
うちにとっては何も変わらんだろ。
Even so,
何も変わらなくても→
that's all we can do.
わたしたちにできることは それで全てです。
And apologize from the bottom of our heart.
あとは 心から　おわびするだけです。
-We're really sorry. -Enough of that.
本当に　すいませんでした。 それは　もういいと言ってるだろ。
But there's nothing else we can do.
でも　ほかにできることは 何もないんです。
We're really sorry.
ホントに 申し訳ございませんでした。
You came all the way from Tokyo just to say that?
そんなこと言うために わざわざ東京から来たのか。
You must have a lot of free time.
暇なやつらだな。
We're very sorry.
（護・かな）申し訳 ございませんでした。
-Thank you.
（彩）ありがとうございました。 （陽介）ありがとうございました。
So Kaoru-chan has book duty and Tomo-kun has flower duty.
（彩）へえ　薫ちゃんが本係で 友君が　お花係なんだ。
What duty did you have, Aya-chan? Me?  I had...
彩ちゃんは何係だったの？ （彩）わたし？　わたしは…。
What did I have?
ねえ　何係だったっけ。
Duty, huh? That was a long time ago. One shiro-ae up.
（陽介）係ね　ずいぶん昔の話だな。 はい　白あえ　上がったよ。
Alright.  Just a minute, okay?
（彩）はい。　ちょっと待っててね。
Didn't you have living creature duty?
（陽介）確か 生き物係じゃなかったか？→
Remember you used to take vegetables to feed the rabbit?
ウサギの餌だとか言って 野菜とか持っていってたろ。
That's right.  I used to take care of Pii-chan, the rabbit.
（彩）そうそう　ウサギのピーちゃん飼ってたんだった。
That sounds so cool.
へえ　いいな。 ≪（戸の開く音）
-Welcome. -Are you full?
（陽介）あっ　いらっしゃい。 （客）いっぱいですか？
If you don't mind the counter, please come in.
（陽介）あっ カウンターでよかったら　どうぞ。
We'll go back upstairs.
（彩）いらっしゃいませ。 わたしたち　上に行くね。
You can stay here as long as you want, you know.
（彩）えっ ずっと　ここにいていいのよ。
But all we're just going to bed so....
でも　もう寝るだけだから。
Mook's there too so we'll be fine.
ムックもいるから大丈夫。
Are you sure? I'll be up later on to check on you then.
（彩）あっ　そう？ じゃ　後で見に行くからね。
Alright.
うん。 分かった。
Here you go, Mook. Sorry it's so late.
はい　ムック　ご飯よ。 遅くなって　ごめんね。
Onee-chan.
お姉ちゃん。 んっ？
You know Cinderella.
シンデレラね。 うん。
She didn't have a real mommy, but I think she had a daddy.。
本当のママはいなかったけど パパはいるみたい。
Did she?
そうだっけ。
See.
ほら。
Is it different from the one I read?
わたしが読んだ本と違うのかな。
It's been a long time since I read "Cinderella."
『シンデレラ』読んだの 昔だからな。
Maybe we are pitiable because
パパもママもいないのって→
we don't have mommy or daddy.
やっぱり僕たち かわいそうなのかも。
What? Really? What a relief.
えっ？　本当ですか？　よかった。
Yes. Alright. Thank you.
はい　分かりました。 ありがとうございました。
What a relief.
よかった。
That was the chief of the PR department.
広報部の部長からです。
Nasu Bungu's president called to tell him
那須文具の社長さん→
that he won't take us to court.
裁判にはしないと 連絡くれたそうです。
-Seriously? -Yes.
マジで？ はい。
-What a relief.
よかった。
Yeah, what a relief. Really, what a relief.
いや～　よかった。 ホントに　よかった。
Marumo's late, isn't he?
マルモ　遅いね。
Yeah, I wonder when he's coming home.
ねっ　いつ帰ってくるんだろう。
Marumo?
≪（ドアの開く音） マルモ？
-Is Takagi-san home? -Not yet.
（彩）高木さん帰ってきた？ まだ。
Oh.  Say, it's starting to rain.
（彩）そう。　あっ　ねえ 雨　降ってきたんだけど→
Is your laundry okay?
洗濯物とか大丈夫？
Rain?
えっ　雨？ （彩）うん。
You're right, it's raining.
あっ　ホントだ　雨だ。
-We don't have any laundry outside. -Okay.
洗濯物は大丈夫だよ。 （彩）うん　分かった。→
Then lock the door and go to bed soon.
じゃ　ちゃんと　鍵　締めて 早めに寝るんだよ。
-Okay, good night. -Good night.
うん　おやすみなさい。 （彩）はい　おやすみ。
What should I do.
どうしよう。
It's coming down, isn't it?
降ってきちゃいましたね。
Takagi-san, thank you so much for coming today.
あっ　高木さん　今日は　ホントに ありがとうございました。
No, no, don't mention it.
いえ　いえ　いえ。
If it's alright with you, shall we have dinner before we go?
あの　よかったら お食事していきませんか？
My treat, as a token of my appreciation.
えっ？ お礼に　わたし　ごちそうします。
Let's go.
行きましょ。 えっ　え～。
Are there any good restaurants around here?
この辺り　いいお店あるかな。
What are you doing?
ねえねえ　どうしたの？
Shh, Mook.  Don't say anything.
しっ　ムック　内緒だよ。
Where are you going?
どこ行くの？
I'll be right back.
すぐ帰ってくるから。
Kaoru.
薫。 んっ？
Huh? Where's Tomoki?
あれ？　友樹は？
Probably the school.
たぶん小学校。
Huh? Why?
えっ？　何で？
Oh no.
大変だ。
[I have a very important business tomorrow.]
《あしたは とっても大事な仕事なんだ》
[I might be a little late getting home, but
《少し　帰りが 遅くなるかもしれないけど→
you two be good and stay home.]
２人とも おとなしく留守番していろよ》
Sansai's up for #3 table.
（陽介）はい　３番さん 山菜　上がったよ。
-Okay. -Katsuo no tataki'* for the counter. (*sashimi with grilled surface)
（彩）はい。 カウンター　カツオのたたき１つ。
Okay, one tataki.
（陽介）はい　たたき１丁。 （彩）はい。
You're gonna be alright now.
もう大丈夫だからね。
[If you water too much, the flower's gonna die, you know.]
《お前な　水は　やり過ぎても お花が死んじゃうんだぞ》
[Really?]
《えっ　そうなの？》
Tomoki. Onee-chan.
友樹。 あっ　お姉ちゃん。
You shouldn't go out without telling anyone.
駄目だよ　勝手にお外に出たら。
But the flower's going to die.
でも　お花が死んじゃうから。
If you catch a cold,
友樹が風邪ひいたら→
there won't be anyone to water it.
あしたから　お水あげる人が いなくなっちゃうよ。
Yeah, you're right.
うん　そうだね。
-Let's go home. -Okay.
帰ろう。 うん。
Are you alright?
（くしゃみ） 大丈夫？
This place is famous for their tacos.
ここのタコスが有名なんですよ。
I'm looking forward to it.
楽しみです。
What a nice restaurant.
わあ　すてきなお店。
Let's party it up tonight.
もう　今日は　ぱあっと いっちゃいましょうよ　ねっ。
Excuse me.
[TEL]（バイブレーターの音） おっ　ちょっと　すいません。
Sorry, I'll be right there,
あっ　すいません すぐ行きますんで→
so go on in first.
先　行っててください。 はい。
-Hello. -Marumo?
もしもし。 [TEL]マルモ？
Yeah.
ああ。
Didn't I tell you I had a very important business today?
今日は大事な仕事があるって 言ったろ。
I think Tomoki caught a cold.
友樹が風邪ひいたみたいなの。
-A cold? -He went out in the rain.
[TEL]風邪？ 雨の中　外に出てったから。
What was he doing? Is he alright?
何だよ　それ。　何やってんだよ。 おい　大丈夫なのか？
I think he's alright.
うん　大丈夫だと思うけど。
Tomoki, it's Marumo.
友樹　マルモ。
Marumo, I'm alright.
マルモ　僕　大丈夫だよ。
Okay. Stay warm and go to bed.
あっ　そっか。 じゃ　あったかくして寝てろ。
See you later then.
じゃあな。　なっ。
Onee-chan, I feel like I'm floating.
お姉ちゃん　何か　ふわふわする。
Go to sleep, Tomoki.
え～　もう寝な　友樹。　ねっ。
Let's get you to bed.
行こう　ベッド。 うん。
What's a family?
家族って何なんだろうね。
Where did that come from?
（陽介）えっ　何だ　突然。
The kids asked me today
（彩）いや 昼間　あの子たちに聞かれたのよ。
if Marumo's their family.
マルモは家族なのかって。
Oh, I see.
（陽介）ああ　そうか。
It caught me by surprise.
どきっとしちゃった。
But even if you're not related by blood, you're family if you live together, right?
でも　他人でも 一緒に住んでれば家族よね。
Well, I guess you become a family as you spend time living together.
まあ　一緒に住んでるうちに 家族になってくもんだよ。
Even a husband and wife aren't
（彩）うん。 （陽介）夫婦だって→
related at all to start out with.
最初は他人だからな。
That's right, huh? Come to think of it,
そうだよね。　考えてみれば→
Mom and Dad aren't related by blood, huh?
お父さんと　お母さんも 血は　つながってないんだもんね。
Family, huh?
家族か。
Even though I failed at it.
わたしは失敗しちゃったけど。
You'll have plenty of opportunity in the future.
まあ　これから　いくらでも チャンスあるだろ。→
You're still young.
お前　まだ若いんだから。
I've already learned my lesson.
もう懲りた。
You're too young to be saying that.
ハァ　その年で言うせりふじゃ ねえだろ　まったく。
In the first place, your marriage was too short.
だいたいな お前の結婚生活は短過ぎたんだよ。
That's why you don't understand anything yet.
だから まだ何にも分かっちゃいないの。→
Two people become true husband and wife only after overcoming difficulties together.
夫婦っていうのはな　２人で色々 乗り越えていってこそなんだよ。
I've had enough.
十分です。
How do you know you've had enough
（陽介）たった１年の結婚生活で 何が→
-after only 1 year of marriage? -Things happened after that too.
じゅうぶん分かったっていうんだ？ （彩）その後にも色々あったの。
And I thought things might work out this time.
今度は　うまくいくと思ったのに。
Are you sure you weren't part of the problem too?
お前にもさ 何か問題があったんじゃないのか。
No I wasn't.
違います。
Tomoki, are you alright?
友樹　大丈夫？
What should I do?
どうしよう。
Go ahead, call him.
電話しちゃいなよ。
What?
えっ？
To our hard day's work.
じゃ　今日は　お疲れさまでした。
Thank you for your hard work.
（かな）お疲れさまでした。
-Cheers.
乾杯。 （かな）乾杯。
But Makimura-san, that is,
でも　牧村さん　あれですよね→
won't your boyfriend get mad if he finds out you're having dinner with me?
こんな食事してたら　彼氏が 怒っちゃうんじゃないすか？
I don't have a boyfriend.
あっ　彼氏　いませんから。
Really? Is that right?
えっ？　そうなんですか？
-Yes. -So you don't...
（かな）はい。 そうなんだ…。
Excuse me! Two tequila here please.
すいません！ テキーラを２つ　ここに。
Right away please.
すぐに持ってきてください。
Excuse me.
ちょっと　すいません。
This is really good.
これ　うまいっすよ　これ。
Don't you have to answer it?
あっ　出なくていいんですか？
No.
ええ。 [TEL]（バイブレーターの音）
Okay, let's drink.
よし　飲みましょう　ねっ。
Excuse me.
ちょっと　すいません。
Hello?
もしもし？
Tomoki's...
[TEL]友樹が。
What's wrong?
どうした。
He's having a hard time breathing. His face is all red too.
[TEL]苦しそうなの　顔が真っ赤で。
What?
えっ？
He's breathing really hard.
ハアハアいってるし。
But he said he was alright, didn't he?
さっき大丈夫って言ったろ？
But...
[TEL]だけど。
-Here you go. -Wait a minute.
≪（店員）お待たせしました。 ちょっと待ってろ。
Marinated cactus, chorizo plate, and
（店員）サボテンのマリネと チョリソーの盛り合わせと→
chicken tacos.
チキンのタコスでございます。
Please go ahead and eat. Sorry.
どうぞ　先に食べちゃってくださいはい　はい　すいません。
-And? -Fever.
で？ [TEL]熱が。
Fever?
熱？
His forehead's really hot and he doesn't look good, Marumo.
[TEL]おでこが　すごく熱くて 苦しそうだよ　マルモ。
Alright, I'll be back as soon as I can. See you.
分かった　なるべく早く帰るから。 じゃあな。
Was it someone from your family?
ご家族の方ですか？
Yes. No... Yes.
ええ。　いや…　はい。
Is someone sick?
ご病気なんじゃ。
But...
でも。
Please don't mind me and go.
行ってあげてください。
I'll be fine.
えっ？ わたしは大丈夫ですから。
Alright.
はい。
I'm sorry. Seems he suddenly got ill from a sudden illness.
すいません　何か　急な急病に 急になっちゃったみたいで。
Sorry, I'm really sorry. Sorry.
すいません　本当に　すいません。 すいません。
Give me a break, guys.
勘弁しろよ　あいつら。
Marumo? Yeah. Is Tomoki alright?
マルモ？ おう。　友樹　大丈夫か？
Hey, he has a really high fever.
おい　すごい熱じゃねえかよ。
Why did he go out in the rain?
何で 雨の中　出掛けたりしたんだよ。
-Because. -He's bound to catch a cold
だって。 そんなことしたら→
if he goes out in this rain.
風邪ひくに決まってんだろ。
But he followed what you told him, Marumo.
だって　友樹 マルモの言ったこと守ったんだよ。
Followed what?
何を。
You said that too much water is not good.
お水　やり過ぎると　駄目だって 言ってたから。
He went to the school to put an umbrella over the flower.
学校に行って　傘　差したの お花に。
He was saying the magical spell too.
あっ。 魔法の呪文も言ってた。
-Magical spell? -The one that goes Woo~ Mambo.
魔法の呪文？ ウ～　マンボってやつ。
What?
えっ？
The classmates were making fun of him but
友達にバカにされたけど→
Tomoki said "Marumo's amazing" and
でも 「マルモは　すごいんだぞ」って→
bragged about you to everyone.
みんなに自慢したんだよ。
What magical spell...
魔法の呪文なんて。
Tomoki, are you stupid? For believing something like that.
友樹　お前　バカじゃないのか？ そんなの信じて。
Why did you believe what I said.
俺の言うことなんか お前　信じやがって。
Tomoki, you...
友樹　お前　なあ。
Hey, hey. Look.
おい。　おい　ちょっと。
Doesn't he look like he's getting worse?
何か どんどん　ひどくなってねえか？
Let's take him to the hospital.
病院　連れてこう。　なっ。
-Now? -Yeah. Okay, Tomoki, you alright?
今から？ ああ。　よし　友樹　大丈夫か？
Excuse me, can you tell me where the closest hospital is?
すいません　病院　教えてください。
-Somewhere I can take him now. -What happened?
今から診てくれる病院。 （陽介）んっ　どうした。
He has a high fever.
高熱みたいで。 （彩）えっ？
What about Nagashima Clinic? They have pediatrics there, don't they?
あっ　長島クリニックどうだ。 あそこなら小児科やってんだろ。
-Oh, yeah. -Nagashima Clinic?
あっ　うん。 長島クリニック？
Yeah, right past the Inari shrine, to the right.
（陽介）ああ　あのな お稲荷さんの先　右だ。
Inari shrine. Got it.
お稲荷さん　分かりました。
I'll go too.  To make sure.
わたしも行ってくる。　心配だから。
Yeah.
ああ。
Here's the Inari shrine.
おっ　お稲荷さんだ。
Tomoki, we're almost there. Hang on.
友樹　もう少しだ　しっかりしろよ。
Takagi-san, not that way. This way, this way.
（彩）高木さん　そっちじゃない。 こっち　こっち。
-What? -This way.
えっ？ こっち。
Hello, I have a sick child. Please open.
すいません　子供が大変です 開けてください。
Sensei, please.
先生　お願いします。
Please.
お願いします。
Excuse me, please. Please open.
すいません　お願いします。 開けてください。
Excuse me, Sensei.
すいません　先生。
It was just a cold.
ただの風邪だってよ。
Looks like we overreacted, huh?
大騒ぎし過ぎちゃったな。
We even got Aya-chan involved.
彩ちゃんまで巻き込んじゃって。
Yes, but I'm relieved.
うん　でも　よかった。
Sorry, Tomoki. You too, Kaoru.
ごめんな　友樹。　薫も。
When I heard he caught a cold, I knew I should come home,
俺　風邪だって聞いて 帰んなきゃって思ったけど→
but I left you two alone.
お前たちだけにしちゃって。
I'm no good after all. I can't do anything.
俺　やっぱ駄目だ。 何にもできねえもん。
I can't take Sasakura's place after all.
笹倉の代わりなんて やっぱり無理なんだよ。
Marumo.
マルモ。
You're not no good.
駄目じゃないもん。
Tomoki was saying over and over while he was sleeping.
だって　友樹 寝てるとき何回も言ってたよ。
He was saying "Marumo"
「マルモ」って。
"Marumo" over and over.
「マルモ」って 何回も言ってたんだよ。
So, so...
だから　だから。
Marumo.
マルモ。
Tomoki, are you alright?
友樹　大丈夫か？
Yes. Thanks for giving me a piggyback ride.
うん ありがとう　おんぶしてくれて。
-Marumo's amazing just as I thought.
マルモ　やっぱり　すごいよ。 えっ？
The flower's starting to sprout.
あのね　お花 ちょっとだけ芽が出てたんだよ。
Wow.
《わあ》
You're alright now.
《もう大丈夫だからね》
It's thanks to Marumo's magical spell.
マルモの魔法の呪文のおかげだね。
I don't have mommy or daddy, but I'm happy because I have Marumo.
僕　パパもママもいないけど マルモがいるから　うれしいよ。
It's okay because Marumo's with us.
うん マルモがいてくれるからいい。
You guys.
お前ら。
Marumo's crying.
マルモが泣いてる。
Sweat. This is sweat.
あっ　これは汗だ　汗。
Ah~ it's hot in here.
あれ？　あ～　あっつい。
-Seconds please. -You sure eat a lot.
お代わり。 おい　よく食うな。
Marumo.
あっ　ねえ　マルモ。 んっ？
I can go to school today, can't I?
今日から 学校　行っていいでしょ？
I took off 3 times already.
もう　３回も休んじゃったよ。
I guess so, since your fever's gone too.
そうだな　熱も下がったしな。
With that kind of an appetite, you should be fine now.
まあ　そんだけ食欲があれば もう大丈夫だろ。　なっ。
What's today's okite? Hm? Today it's...
今日のおきては何？ んっ？　今日はね。
Gargle, wash hands, don't catch a cold.
うがい　手洗い　カゼひかない。
Prevention is the key.
風邪はな　予防が大切なんだ。
But if you don't feel well, you have to tell me right away, okay?
でも　もし体調が悪かったら すぐに言うんだぞ。
Got it.
分かった。 うん。
It's a superstition when they say fools don't catch colds.
バカは風邪ひかないってのは あれは迷信だな。
-What does that mean? -Huh? Never mind.
どういう意味？ んっ？　まあ　それはいいとして。
Okay, we're all gonna make a promise.
よし　じゃ　みんな　約束だ。
Come.
こい。
Am I catching a cold?
あれ　何か風邪かな。
-Marumo.
マルモ。
Marumo?
マルモ？
Are you alright?
大丈夫？